Finding Aid for William D. Corson Papers 1896-1926
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William D. Corson Papers 1896-1926
Corson, William D.
5 linear in. and 1 oversize folder
Soldier with the 31st Michigan Volunteer Infantry during the Spanish-American War. War-related documents, including bills, orders and passes, and pension applications; also financial materials, 1901-1902, relating to his involvement in the Ann Arbor Gun Club; and photographs.
8789 Aa 2 UAm
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of William T. Bronson (donor no. 5756 ) and came to the library in September 1986.
The collection is open for research.
William D. Corson was a soldier with the 31st Michigan Volunteer Infantry during the Spanish-American War. Trained in Chattanooga, Tennessee, the Michigan 31st served in Cuba during the war. After the war, Corson became proprietor of Corson's Cozy Corner saloon which was located at the northwest corner of Ann and Main Street in Ann Arbor, Michigan.
The William D. Corson collection is primarily an accumulation of the momentos of a number of the men of the 31st Michigan Volunteer Infantry. Materials include newspaper clippings concerning the Michigan 31st both in Chattanooga and in Cuba, bills of purchases by the commissary in Cuba (many of these for cigars), orders and passes issued through the office of Captain Ross Granger, souvenirs, and photographs.
The collection also contains insurance policies, including those from the period of Corson's duty during the Spanish-American War and pension applications for veterans of the war. These applications were solicited by law firms and seem to represent a thriving local industry.
The rest of the collection contains material collected after the Spanish-American War when Corson was a saloon proprietor. Included are photographs of the saloon taken around 1910. Corson was also the secretary and treasurer of the Ann Arbor Gun Club and kept shooting scores, bills, receipts and an account book of the club. An oversized group portrait shows Corson and other members of the club.
In addition, the collection includes photographs of family and friends, Ann Arbor scenes, a group portrait of the veterans of the 31st Michigan Volunteer Infantry, and photos of military activities, while training in the United States and while stationed in Cuba. A number of advertising cards for several local Ann Arbor businesses are included and probably date prior to 1910.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor Gun Club (Mich.); Spanish-American War, 1898; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 31st (1898-1899)
Subjects - Visual Material:
Ann Arbor Gun Club (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor Railroad Company.; Argo Mills (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Business enterprises--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Corson, William D.; Corson's Cozy Corner Saloon (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Hotels and taverns--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Interiors.; Military camps.; Railroad accidents.; Spanish-American War, 1898; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 31st (1898-1899)
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Thirty-first Michigan Volunteer Infantry, ca. 1896-1926
  - Newspaper Clippings, ca. 1898 (Box 1)
  - Bills, ca. 1898-1899, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Orders and Passes, 1898-1901 (Box 1)
  - Momentos, 1897-1926 (Box 1)
  - Insurance Policies, 1896-1898 (Box 1)
  - Pension Applications, 1898-1899 (Box 1)
- Ann Arbor Gun Club, 1901-1902
  - Scores, Bills and Receipts, 1901-1902 (Box 1)
  - Account Book, ca. 1901-1902 (Box 1)
- Photographs, ca. 1898-ca. 1910
  - Thirty-first Michigan Volunteer Infantry, ca. 1897-1898 (Box 1)
  - Spanish-American War, 1897-1898 (Box 1)
  - Veterans of Thirty-first Volunteer Infantry (Box 1)
    (in oversized folder UAm)
  - Ann Arbor Gun Club (Box 1)
  - Corson's Cozy Corner Saloon, ca. 1910 (Box 1)
    (also in oversized folder UAm)
  - Personal (unidentified and undated) (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor (unidentified and undated) (Box 1)
  - Advertising cards (prior to 1910) (Box 1)